# JACOB BARRETT DEMING

609-203-9531 · JacobDeming91@gmail.com

Extremely motivated Media Studies and Coding Bootcamp graduate with extensive knowledge of programming, web design, and game design principles seeking a full-time position within Game Development. Proficient in JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Java, Unity, and Angular 2, as shown through my over six years of working alongside and within the tech and gaming industries.

#### **EDUCATION**

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey
Major: Journalism and Media Studies
Minor: Cinema Studies
Cumulative GPA: 3.82, Magna Cum Laude and Dean's List
Member, Kappa Tau Alpha National Honor Society in Journalism and Mass Communications
Recipient of the distinguished Journalism and Media Studies Endowed Fund

New Brunswick, NJ
B.A. May 2014
May 2014

May 2014
Recipient of the distinguished Journalism and Media Studies Endowed Fund

New Brunswick, NJ
B.A. May 2014

July 2013

**Rutgers Coding Bootcamp** 

Recipient of Academic Excellence Award

New Brunswick, NJ

Full Stack Web Development

July 2016

April 2012

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.

Skills Learned: JavaScript, jQuery, Node, Express, HTML5/CSS3, Bootstrap, Git, Lodash, Responsive Design, API/JSON, Firebase, MySQL, Angular 2, Materialize, and MongoDB.

Topics Covered: Database Theory, API's, Agile Methodologies, Presentation Skills, Research Methods, System Administration, Quality Assurance Testing, Social Coding Best Practices, and Computer Science.

## RELEVANT SKILLS

- Game Design: Adept in the process of designing gameplay elements, implementing them into a system, and balancing the product through the processes of user feedback and testing. Deep understanding of gaming theory, law, narrative, and production. Proficient in JavaScript, Typescript, Node, Angular 2, Unity, Adobe Flash Professional, Java, HTML, and CSS.
- Research: Strong research skills ranging from quantitative to qualitative analysis of data. Experienced fact checker, ethnographer, and market analyst. Proficient in Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, and Prezi.
- Writing: Robust writing and editing skills extending to all forms of publication including journalism, reviews, screenplays, scholarly articles, blog posts, and online narratives followed by over 400 unique users.
- Video Production: Experienced in all aspects of developing multimedia content from conception through post-production. Proficient in video, photo, and audio recording with wide variety of equipment. Skilled with Final Cut Pro, Sony Vegas Pro, Adobe Premiere Pro, Fraps, Sony Sound Forge, Adobe Audition, Audacity, and film projection systems.

### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Trilogy Education Services** *Programming Consultant*

New York, NY

April 2016 – Present

- Creates detailed JavaScript, Node, MySQL, and HTML lesson plans for use in a boot-camp setting
- Produces coding activities and comments solutions for those assignments created
- Reviews, updates, and modernizes old and outdated lesson plans and code to higher standards

**Starboard Games LLC** PR Lead

Midlothian, VA

August 2015 – April 2016

- Directed PR campaigns for an independent game studio by providing weekly agendas, goals, and assignments
- · Managed newsletters, blogs, and provided outreach to additional communities to extend the company's reach
- Handled social media and provided regular updates on the narrative and technical aspects of the product

**Big Tent Entertainment** 

New York, NY Summer 2013

Game Marketing Intern
 Helped to test, market, and successfully launch a mobile game on the Apple App Store

- Conducted market analysis on gaming and mobile applications industry
- Created design documents and presentations for possible future projects

### LEADERSHIP

# Rutgers Game Swap "Level Up!"

New Brunswick, NJ

Co-Founder

Spring 2012, 2013, 2014 & 2015

- Worked with Rutgers Student Life to organize and run the popular annual gaming swap-meet at Geek Week
- Designed posters and flyers for the events whilst publicizing them through social media
- Managed and traded an average of 200 to 300 titles per event

### Plangere Writing Center, Rutgers University

Tutor and Session Chief

New Brunswick, NJ September 2011 – May 2014

- Selected as an intern for Fall 2011, promoted to Session Chief, Spring 2013
- Tutored Students in Basic Composition, Expository Writing, and Research in Disciplines